In this demo we will explore the different features available in the collab extension.
On the screen, there's a one page Google Doc
with about six paragraphs.
There are several comments and suggested edits in the document.
And two coauthors are right now active in this document.
First, we want to know who is active in
0:00:20.160,0:00:22.903
K
Screen reader: anonymous walrus is on page one paragraph five and line one
Screen reader: anonymous liger is on page one paragraph two and line one
So the screen reader told us the location of the coauthors
I want to know what my coauthors are doing,
However I don't want to lose my cursor
position.
To do that, I can press ctrl shift H
Screen reader: Following anonymous walrus
The screen reader told me that I'm now following anonymous walrus
I can hear a typing sound as anonymous walrus writes
which means that I can get a sense about when they're contributing to a document
and when they're off doing something else.
[Typing sound]
Screen reader: Hello world. This is a test sentence.
After they finish writing a line, I can hear what they just wrote on the past line.
Now I want to jump to anonymous walrus's location to explore these edits more.
I can do that by pressing control shift one.
Screen reader: Moved cursor to anonymous walrus's location at page one paragraph six and line one.
And here my screen reader told me that I've moved to anonymous walrus's cursor location
I can repeatedly press ctrl shift H to rotate through the list of all active coauthors
and select who I want to follow and eventually stop following any other coauthors.
Now I want to explore the relative proximity cues which notifies me
where my coauthors are relative to my location so that I don't type over other's edits.
We have four different ways to get relative proximity notifications.
I'll first select the spoken announcement option.
Screen reader: spoken announcement
0:02:01.840,0:02:07.000
0:02:07.000,0:02:09.040
0:02:10.560,0:02:12.508
0:02:12.508,0:02:15.520
0:02:16.400,0:02:19.000
0:02:19.000,0:02:23.019
0:02:23.019,0:02:26.320
0:02:27.840,0:02:30.531
0:02:30.531,0:02:35.840
0:02:37.840,0:02:45.120
0:02:45.120,0:02:51.000
0:02:51.000,0:02:57.040
0:02:57.040,0:03:00.027
features,
Screen reader: musical note pitch change selected,
as anonymous walrus enters my paragraph, I'll hear a musical note
If they come to the line where I have my cursor, a slightly higher pitched note occurs.
If they place their cursor at the exact same spot where I am, an even higher pitched note happens.
If they move away from my paragraph, then I hear a lower pitched note.
What if anonymous liger enters my paragraph?
So we hear tones of different
0:03:45.120,0:03:51.360
that is distinct from anonymous walrus's,
musical note changed with
relative proximity between our cursors.
So the closer the coauthor comes to my cursor, the higher the pitch gets.
What will happen though if the note
0:04:05.296,0:04:08.507
0:04:08.507,0:04:12.485
0:04:12.485,0:04:19.160
0:04:19.160,0:04:24.360
0:04:24.360,0:04:31.440
0:04:31.440,0:04:35.760
0:04:36.560,0:04:40.240
0:04:40.240,0:04:43.944
0:04:43.944,0:04:48.199
0:04:48.199,0:04:52.000
cursors,
because I want to navigate by paragraph,
Screen reader: Presentation option, Paragraph scroll bar selected.
Now I'll press ctrl shift U to invoke the audio scroll bar,
Screen reader: audio scroll bar turned on
The screen reader told me that the audio scroll bar is turned on,
Now I'll press the up or down arrow key to get an audio indication of which paragraph has more or less comments,
The next paragraph has two comments,
So we hear a higher pitched sound.
And then the next paragraph has four comments, and so we hear a much higher pitched sound.
If we go to the last paragraph, there's
0:05:54.720,0:05:57.341
0:05:57.341,0:06:01.200
0:06:01.200,0:06:05.840
0:06:07.040,0:06:09.680
about the comments or edits in the paragraph
I can press ctrl M after hearing the tone,
other cursors, and four edits.
And the screen reader told me the number of edits, comments, and cursors in the paragraph.
If I want to move my cursor to a paragraph to explore in more detail, I can press ctrl shift one.
Screen reader: Moved to page one paragraph seven.
I also want to check what happens if we
0:06:35.400,0:06:38.289
0:06:38.289,0:06:41.120
0:06:41.120,0:06:43.800
0:06:43.800,0:06:50.113
keys to get an audio indication of which paragraph has more or less comments,
And then the next paragraph has
four comments. So we hear four tones.
For five or more comments, we'll just hear five tones.
So this way, using the audio scroll bar we can get a quick overview of how comments or edits are distributed in the document.